- [Instructor] So we've
added these physics materials
to our player and our enemies
so that way when they collide
it creates this bouncy bump.
Now we need to make it so that the enemy
can actually chase the
player around the scene.
So we're going to use a script to do that.
In our project window,
we're going to go into our scripts folder,
we're going to right-click
and create a new C sharp script.
And for this we'll just call it enemy.
So this will hold all the behaviors
that the enemy should manage.
And we're going to make
sure we click and drag
the enemy script onto the enemy.
And you can see it's been applied.
So now we're going to
go into our enemy script
by opening it up.
Now in our enemy script,
let's think about some of
the things that we wanna do.
So we're going to need a speed
to be able to make the enemy move.
So we'll make this another public
so we can fix it in the editor.
Float speed and we'll set this to,
we'll set it a little slower,
so make it three for now.
Another thing we need to do
is because we're going to
try and move this object
we need the rigid body component.
So we need a private rigid body.
And we'll just call this enemy RB.
And now we need to
actually get the reference
of that rigid body on the object.
So we use our enemy RB variable
and we set that to the component
of our rigid body on our enemy.
Now we need to move this enemy.
To actually visualize what
we're trying to do here,
we're trying to move the
enemy from their position
to our player's position.
Now if we think about it in terms
of how we apply the force,
since we're trying to move our enemy
towards the player, we
should take our player's
current position and then
we need to subtract it
from our enemy's position.
So in fact, we actually need
a reference to our player.
Since we don't have to find our player,
we'll make this a private variable
and this will just be the game object.
And we'll just call it the player.
In our start method, we need
to find that actual player.
So we'll use our player variable.
And we set that to the
game object in our scene,
we find it by it's name,
which in this case we named it player.
So now we have the reference to our player
and so now we need to apply a force
in the direction of our player.
So we need our rigid body again
and we add a force
and how we're going to add this force
is we're going to take
our player's position.
So we need to use player
and we get the transform
to get their current position.
And we're going to subtract by
our enemy's current position,
so we need our transform here.
And we need the position.
So now we know the direction
that we're trying to go
by subtracting our player's position
from the current enemy position.
So that will give us the
vector three coordinates
that we need to go towards at all times.
In this case, we're
going to apply our speed
so that way we know how fast
the enemy should be moving.
One thing to consider is
because this is actually a math equation,
so our computer will read
this as a math equation.
It will actually follow standard rules.
So because transform.position
is being multiplied
by speed, it'll actually do that first
before it subtracts from the position.
So that's not what we want to happen.
We want to get the direction
that we're trying to go to
before we apply the speed.
So we use parentheses so
then that way make sure
that first we're going to
subtract the player's position
and our current position and then
we're going to multiply that vector three
by a certain speed.
Now let's make sure we save.
And then in unity, if we play our game,
we should see the enemy is very,
very aggressively rolling towards us.
So that's good.
Now one of the things that you might see
is it was going very fast.
Now the reason that happens is because
as the player gets farther
away from the enemy,
the length of that actual vector,
the distance between those
two positions becomes larger
and so what it actually does, is it tries
to multiply it over a very
large amount of distance.
So it actually increases
in force over time.
We can actually use some code
to prevent that from happening.
So what we're gonna do is
we're going to actually
create a standard strength
so that way even if the enemy is
really far away from the player,
it doesn't actually get
an increased magnitude,
an increased strength
of it's force over time
because the distance is larger.
We can use a .normalized
after this vector three,
so this will actually
normalize the magnitude of this vector,
so it doesn't matter how close
or how far the enemy is from the player,
it will always be coming
at the same speed.
So if we save.
So now in unity when we press play,
we should see that the
enemy doesn't move at a
very fast speed, it doesn't
accelerate really quickly
when it runs into the player.
Which is exactly what we want.
So now it's your turn.
You're going to go into your assets folder
in your scripts and make an enemy script.
Make sure you apply that enemy script
to your enemy as a component.
In your editor, you're going
to create three new variables,
so we're gonna get a speed variable,
we're going to get the rigid body,
we're going to get a
reference to the player.
In our start method, make sure that you
get the component for that rigid body
and make sure that you find that player
in the game hierarchy.
And then in our update method,
you're going to add a force
to the enemy's rigid body.
And you're going to get
the player's position,
subtract our current position,
so that we get a direction
we're trying to go to.
Make sure that you put both
of those in parentheses.
So that way it does that operation first.
You're going to .normalized
so that way we can actually
normalize that vector
so it doesn't accelerate
at a very fast speed
the farther the two objects are away.
And then we're gonna multiply
it by the speed that we set.
Now it's your turn.